# **Varun Narayanswamy**

## Design Engineer/Software Engineer

https://varunnar.github.io/ | varunk.narayanswamy@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/varun-narayanswamy/ (720)-490-2346 |. Seattle, WA

#### PROFESSION EXPERIENCE

I am a software engineer and designer with over three years of experience as a full-stack engineer. I hold a Master's degree in Human-Computer Interaction and Design from the University of Washington. I am passionate about working on user-facing technology that increase functionality, accessibility, and delight.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Lab Researcher

University of Washington: Make4All Lab | March 2024 - August 2024

- Advised by Jennifer Mankoff
- Researched and prototyped an educational app using Figma and data visualization development that uses student data to identify habits affecting GPA and suggests improvements. Conducted qualitative research study to better understand the application value and potential concerns.

## **Software Engineer Contractor**

VitalsMatter | March 2023 - August 2023

 Developed backend architecture with MySQL authentication, designed web interfaces in Figma, and researched health-tracking wearables to futureproof a mobile application for at-risk populations.

## Software Engineer II

Seagate Technology | May 2019 - September 2022

 Fullstack development (Vue.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript) for data management and security. Built out user facing features, designed MongoDB database integrations and helped lead the team in developing the Selenium test framework and communication with cloud storage containers.

## SELECTED PROJECTS

# **Visualizing Wellness**

Visualization of the **GLOBEM** Dataset

 Parsed 6 years of UW student mental health, physical states and activity data. Developed visualization using Vegalite that assist in gleaning actionable insights.

## **Project Tightrope**

Interactive Education Experience Regard the Physical/Mental Experience of Anxiety

Designed and developed Multiplayer walk-up-and-play style videogame.
Players either use a balancing board and rod to dodge/collect negative and positive orbs, or wing controllers to move orbs towards player one. Led software and hardware code development and contributed to ideation and refinement.

## HeartbeatChecker

iOS Mobile Application for easy and Accessible Heartbeat Checking

• iOS Mobile app that uses photoplethysmography, the Swift AVFoundations video recording, and iPhone flashlight to check the heart rate.

## **EDUCATION**

## **University of Washington**

Master's in Human Computer Interaction + Design

Class of 2024 | Seattle, WA

## University of Colorado, Boulder

Bachelor's in Creative Technology + Design

- Class of 2020 | Boulder, CO
- Minors: Applied Math, Computer Science

## SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

## **Software Development:**

Languages:

JavaScript, Typescript, Vue.js, Python, Swift, HTML, CSS, D3, MakeCode, C++, React

Software and Tools:
S3, Kubernetes, Jenkins, OAuth
2.0, MySQL, node, gRPC

## **Prototyping and Design:**

Digital:

Figma, InDesign, Photoshop, Logic, CapCut, iMovie

Physical:

Adafruit CPX, laser cutting, 3D Printing, Circuitry, Soldering, Rhinoceros

## **User Research:**

 Usability Testing, Semistructured Interview, Contextual Inquiry, Affinity Mapping, Thematic Analysis

## **HONORS & ACTIVITIES**

# **Boy Scouts of America**

Troup 78 Boulder, CO